$(document).ready(function () {
    var answered = false;
    var unanswered = 0;
    var correct = 0;
    var incorrect = 0;
    var intervalId;
    var seconds = 10;
    var index = 0;
    var trivia;

    var ootTrivia = [
        {
            question: "Where was Link born?",
            answers: ["Kokiri Forest", "Hyrule", "Gerudu Valley", "Kakariko Village"],
            correct: 1
        },
        {
            question: "Where did Link learn to play the 'Song of Storms?'",
            answers: ["Lake Hyrule", "Death Mountain", "Inside the Windmill", "Desert Wasteland"],
            correct: 2
        },
        {
            question: "Which year was Ocarina of Time released?",
            answers: ["1998", "1992", "2000", "1995"],
            correct: 0
        },
        {
            question: "How many years did Link remain in the Spiritual Realm after drawing the Master Sword?",
            answers: ["fourteen", "seven", "four", "three"],
            correct: 1
        },
        {
            question: "After Link found and killed all 100 Gold Skultas, what was his reward?",
            answers: ["Giant's Wallet", "Golden Scale", "200 rupees", "Golden Gauntlets"],
            correct: 2
        },
        {
            question: "What special weapon does Link need to use to defeat Ganon at the end of the game?",
            answers: ["Arrows of Light", "Goron Hammer", "Bombshoes", "Faore's Wind"],
            correct: 0
        },
        {
            question: "What gift does Princess Zelda give to Link when they first meet?",
            answers: ["The Ocarina of Time", "a hand written letter", "Zelda's Lullaby", "a new hat"],
            correct: 1
        },
        {
            question: "Which number installment is Ocarina of Time in The Legend of Zelda Series?",
            answers: ["first", "second", "fifth", "fourth"],
            correct: 2
        },
        {
            question: "Which TV series was Ocarina of Time inspired by?",
            answers: ["Twin Peaks", "Buffy the Vampire Slayer", "On the Air", "The X-Files"],
            correct: 0
        },
        {
            question: "What was the name of the Graveyard keeper?",
            answers: ["Milo", "Ingo", "Grog", "Damp√©"],
            correct: 3
        }
    ]

    function displayQuestion() {

        $("#results").html("");

        //displays each question and eaach answer selection in browser
        $("#question").html(ootTrivia[index].question);
        $("#choice1").html(ootTrivia[index].answers[0]);
        $("#choice2").html(ootTrivia[index].answers[1]);
        $("#choice3").html(ootTrivia[index].answers[2]);
        $("#choice4").html(ootTrivia[index].answers[3]);

        //assigns attribute to answer selections, labeling all of them witht he correct answer
        const answer = ootTrivia[index].answers[ootTrivia[index].correct];
        $(".answer").attr("data-correct", answer);
    }

    function displayEndResults() {
        clearInterval(intervalId);
        //removes trivia game and shows end of game results
        
        $("#trivia").hide();
        index = 0;
        displayQuestion();

        $("#results").html("<h1>CORRECT: " + correct + "</h1><h1>INCORRECT: " + incorrect + "</h1>");
        $("#results").append('<img src="https://media0.giphy.com/media/TRtXbqJpUnFPq/giphy.gif?cid=790b761180ccc98235cc61ad0b0d03f84b7b004a6b304ded&rid=giphy.gif" style="width: 50%">');
        $("#results").append('<button id="try-again">Try again?</button>');
        restartGame();
    }

  
    
    
    function commence() {
        intervalId = setInterval(decrement, 1000);
    }
    
    function decrement() {
        seconds--;
        $("#time-remaining").html("<h2>Time: " + seconds + "</h2>");
        if (seconds === 0 && index < 9) {
            clearInterval(intervalId);
            incorrect++;
            incrementGame();
            displayQuestion();
            seconds = 10;
            commence();
        } else if (seconds === 0 && index === 9) {
            console.log("yoyoyoy")
            clearInterval(intervalId);
            incorrect++;
            displayEndResults();
        }
        
    }
    
    function incrementGame() {
        index++;
        clearInterval(intervalId);
        displayQuestion();
    }
    
    
    $(document).on('click', '.answer', function () {
        
        var answerSelected = $(this).text();
        console.log(answerSelected);
        
        var correctAnswer = $(this).attr('data-correct');
        console.log(correctAnswer);
        
        
        if (answerSelected === correctAnswer) {
            correct++;
        } else {
            incorrect++;
        }
        
        if (index < 9) {
            seconds = 10;
            incrementGame();
            commence();
        } else {
            displayEndResults();
        }
    })
    
    function restartGame() {
    $("#try-again").on('click', function () {
        seconds = 10;
        $("#time-remaining").html("");
        commence();
        correct = 0;
        incorrect = 0;
        index = 0;
        $("#results").html("");
        $("#trivia").show();
    });}

    displayQuestion();
    commence();
    
    
});
;